Juan L. Sanchez

SAS Consultant at OCS Consulting

Summary

Juan is an accomplished technical SAS consultant with solid experience in SAS and Business Intelligence (BI). Juan started his career as a JAVA developer and progressed in the area of BI and SAS programming. In his most recent SAS role Juan gained extensive experience in the area of platform architecture, installation, configuration, administration, migration and security.

Industries:

- Finance (Banking & Insurance)
- Government
- Telecommunications

Some of the key skills of Juan are:

- Experience with SAS platform installation, configuration and administration
- Experience with various Business Intelligence tools, both inside and outside SAS
- Extensive technical experience and all-round computer knowledge
- Extensive programming experience with various (object-oriented) languages
- Team player, but able to work independently when required

Experience

Senior SAS Consultant (Via OCS Consulting) at CZ

December 2015 - Present (7 months)

- Administration and maintenance of the set of SAS 9.3 and SAS 9.4 solutions (EBI/EDI, GRID Platform, Fraud Framework, EGRC, ECM, Analytics);
- Installation and upgrades of different SAS Solutions;
- Efficient problem solving and implementation of different advanced security configurations;
- Support with strategic and operational decisions.

Senior SAS Consultant at OCS Consulting B.V.

November 2013 - Present (2 years 8 months)

Several projects and roles for internal purposes and for customers, with a wide range of complexity variations.

Focus on a good customer's experience by delivering high quality services and building up strong and long term relationships.

SAS Technical Lifecycle Management Consultant (Via OCS Consulting) at SAS

November 2013 - Present (2 years 8 months)

Several projects for clients of the SAS Institute.

- Installation, configuration (security) and upgrade of all SAS environments (Development, Test, Acceptance and Production);
- Migration of SAS platform;
- Testing and technical documentation;
- Maintenance and technical support.

SAS Consultant / SAS Administrator (via OCS Consulting) at DSW Zorgverzekeraar

November 2013 - Present (2 years 8 months)

Several roles and projects involving:

- Architecture designs;
- Administration and maintenance of the set of SAS solutions (BI, Data Integration, Visual Analytics, Fraud Framework):
- Several migrations from SAS 9.2 to SAS 9.3;
- Installation and upgrades of different SAS Solutions (Data Integration, LSF, Visual Analytics);
- Implementation of different security configurations;

Senior SAS Technical Lifecycle Management Consultant (Via OCS Consulting) at Sanoma Media April 2015 - July 2015 (4 months)

Migration of the Development/Test and Production environments to SAS 9.4 M2, involving several SAS Solutions as SAS EBI/EDI, SAS Customer Intelligence and SAS Visual Analytics, Administration and Reporting.

- Change of the architecture/deployment of the SAS environment.
- Migration and update of the data from SQL Server to PostgreSQL.

Advisement and support on SAS administration concerns as:

- SAS server/platform performance
- PostgreSQL server performance
- Authorization matrix definition and implementation
- Other advanced functional and technical topics of interest

SAS Consultant at Unigarant (Via OCS Consulting)

December 2014 - January 2015 (2 months)

Migration of the Development/Test and Production environments from SAS 9.2 EBI to SAS 9.4 EBI. Advisement and support on BI administration concerns as: - SAS server/platform performance - Authorization matrix definition and implementation - Other functional and technical topics of interest

BI Architect at ITBI - Services

BI SAS Architect at Liberty Seguros

July 2011 - December 2012 (1 year 6 months)

BI Architect, SAS Specialist, Project management for the architecture, quality and new application areas, SAS platform management and business/development support. Improvements in the life cycle of SAS applications, platform development, platform security analysis, collaboration and coordination of Architecture, Support, Projects and Business departments. SOS GmbH JobScheduler and LSF administrator and trainer. Software and hardware platform management.

BI & J2EE Consultant at Innova-tsn

December 2008 - July 2011 (2 years 8 months)

Java Analyst and Project Manager in BI environment, specialist and architect of BI platforms, BI trainer in the areas data mining (SAS analytics platform) and platform management (SAS Management Console). Presentation and product documentation for SAS DataFlux (data Quality). Depth analysis of Oracle BI products and DataFlux. Research of the new BI markets. Clients: Liberty Seguros, ONO Telecomunications, Crédito y caución, Produban (Santander Group), Caja de Burgos, ENAGAS, Innova-TSN

J2EE Consultant at Software AG

June 2008 - December 2008 (7 months)

JAVA analyst and programmer, development of project documentation, management and troubleshooting in collaboration with the Dept. of project and quality management.

Client: INSS (National Institute of Social Security)

J2EE Consultant at VASS

September 2006 - June 2008 (1 year 10 months)

JAVA analyst and programmer and trainer, collaboration with the Department of Architecture, troubleshooting, supervision and support to the development teams.

Clients: Línea Directa Aseguradora, Telefónica Soluciones, ICEX

Certifications

SAS Certified Platform Administrator for SAS 9

License PA001159v9 January 2015

SAS Certified Platform Administrator for SAS 9

License PA001159v9 February 2015

Courses

BI & J2EE Consultant

Innova-tsn
SAS Macros

Senior SAS Consultant

OCS Consulting B.V.
SAS Grid Platform Administration
Workshop: SAS Visual Analytics- Advanced configuration

Languages

Español

(Native or bilingual proficiency)
(Full professional proficiency)

Inglés

Projects

Several projects for clients of OCS Consulting and SAS Institute

November 2013 to Present

Members: Juan Luis Sánchez Hernández, Jelle Daemen, Raymond Ebben, Michael Gomes, Javier Rodríguez Soto, Pieter Vernooij, Mike Vervuren, Dino B., Marcel Jorissen, Ivo Kuijpers, André van de Riet, CBIP, Martin Doughty, Marc Meels, Ignacio Rodriguez Sanchez, Michael Dragonetti, Daniel Kuiper

Role: Technical consultant

Technology: SAS platform and SAS solutions

SAS version: 9.1.3, 9.2, 9.3, 9.4

SAS solutions: BI, Data Integration, Visual Analytics, Office Analytics, Fraud Framework, Customer

Intelligence

OS: UNIX, Linux and Windows Servers

Project summary:

Leading the administration, migration and installation of SAS platform for several projects. (e.g. companies from insurance, environmental care, governmental and technology areas).

Responsibilities:

- Architecture designs;
- Platform Administration;
- Installation, configuration, maintenance and support;
- Migration, version upgrades and server moves;

- Implementation of several advanced SAS security configurations (metadata, OS, web security, communications, access authorizations, synchronization with Active Directory/LDAP, IWA, Single Sign On, Reverse Proxy, 2FA, etc);
- Establish connectivity to data sources;
- Technical testing and documentation;

Business Intelligence Administrator @ Santander Group (via Innova-TSN)

May 2011 to December 2011

Members: Juan Luis Sánchez Hernández, Luis Álvarez Sevillano

Role: Administrator of SAS, BO and PentaHo solutions for banking

Technology: SAS platform and SAS solutions, Business Objects, Excelsius, Pentaho, Proclarity

OS: AIX, Linux RedHat

servers: more than 50 servers (Development, Test and Production)

Project summary:

Administration, installation of the different SAS, BO and PentaHo platforms for the complete set of countries where Santander Group provides service).

Responsibilities:

- Administration;
- Installation, configuration, maintenance and support;
- Version upgrades and server moves;
- Establish connectivity to data sources;
- Technical testing and documentation;
- ICT departments coordination.

Technical design and lead on SAS platforms and solutions migration to SAS 9.4 M2 with change of the architecture

June 2015 to Present

Members: Juan Luis Sánchez Hernández, Ivo Kuijpers, Ivo van den Berg, Monica de Kaper, Hans Waterham, Erik Blankers, Karsten de Vries, Rob Graveland, Robert Glintmeijer

Skills & Expertise

SAS Administration

SAS

DB₂

Training

Platform Architecture

Platform Integration

Bases de datos

UML

Coordination

Server Administration

ITIL

Programación SAS

Calidad de datos

SAS Technical Life-Cycle Management

MySQL

Java

Business Objects

Java EE

SAS Base

SAS programming

Databases

Data Quality

Project Management

HTML

JavaScript

Job Scheduling

J2EE Application Development

Tortoise SVN

WebSphere Application Server

JBoss Application Server

AIX Administration

Linux

Red Hat Linux

Windows Server

Content Management

IT Service Management

Change Management

RUP Methodologies

Oracle SQL

WAMP

Serena Changeman

JSP

JSF

Pentaho

Communication

Leadership

Self-driven

Confidentiality

Database Administration

Education

Universidad Pontificia de Salamanca

Ingeniero Técnico en Informática de Gestión, con grado, Information Technology, 2001 - 2006

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Ingeniero Técnico en Informática de Gestión, Computer Engineering, 1999 - 2001

Interests

Oracle, SAS, J2EE, SAP, nuevas tecnologías, desarrollo aplicaciones móviles, arquitectura IT

Juan L. Sanchez

SAS Consultant at OCS Consulting



Contact Juan L. on LinkedIn